

Sergio Asensio

Mathematician and Software Analyst Developer with a solid background in web applications development and several programming areas such as: Full Stack Developer (FRONTEND, BACKEND), Web Designer, Web Services Implementation (REST/SOAP), Database Management...

During my 4 years of experience, I have attended multiple projects managed by different technologies such as Java, Angular, Salesforce and NodeJS. Moreover, I have plenty of experience working in some projects on my own and also with qualified teams that they helped me in my professional and personal growth.

As a full stack technical analyst, some of my main tasks are: Analysis and implementation of the FRONTEND and BACKEND functionalities in the most simple and efficient way. Also I have been in charge of defining the database tables structure as well as the relation between them. Moreover, I established the code architecture of main project modules in order to take them as referents to develop new ones and support and knowledge transfer to team's software developers...But these are only some of the things I used to do in each project.

I am a so persistent person with my objectives and this is precisely the aspect that I like most about my work, I see my day by day as challenges to defeat and the more innovative and challenging they are the more motivated I am.

Zaragoza (Spain)

0

678-154-765



maserasen@gmail.com



sergio-asensio-in



sergio-asensio-cv

EDUCATION

2011 - 2016

Bachelor of Mathematics - Zaragoza University

LANGUAGES

Spanish

Mother tongue

English

Speaking and writting upper-intermediate level

SOFTWARE TOOLS

Lava

Spring MVC – Spring Hibernate – Spring Boot – Maven – JSF –JPA – jQuery – AJAX – Javascript – Quarz – Apache Tomcat

Salesforce Angular 7 Apex – Visualforce – Heroku – Marketing Cloud – Schedule Jobs

Typescript – Npm – Reactive Forms – NgModules – Observables & Promises

NodeJS Web Design Web Services BBDD ETL

Code Editor
Task Management
Version Control

Express.js – Nodemon – Babel-Node – Knex.js – Objection.js

HTML – JSP – JSPX – CSS – SCSS – Bootstrap 4 – Font Awesome 4– ChartJS

REST - SOAP

PostgreSQL-Oracle-SQL

Talend

Eclipse – Intellij – Visual Studio Code

Jira

Git – Github – Gitlab – Bitbucket – SVN – CVS

WORK EXPERIENCE

May 2019-Present

SOFTWARE ANALYST DEVELOPER - (Grupo Oesia)

 Technical full stack analyst and referent in a residue management project for Aragón government. My main role is focused on the definition and implementation of the architecture and functionalities of the FRONTEND (Angular 7) and BACKEND (Spring Boot -JPA) modules of the project as well as the support and knowledge transfer to team's software developers.

March 2018 - May 2019

SOFTWARE SENIOR DEVELOPER – (Grupo Oesia)

- Technical analysis and development of several Angular (Angular 7) modules and Java REST services (Spring Boot -JPA) that were required within an environmental quality and waste management app.
- Main and only responsible of a final client proyect where I was in charge of the expansion of several functionalities related to Zaragoza's civil service app (PrimeFaces JSPX SQL).

February 2017- March 2018

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER - (DxD Applications & IT Solutions)

- Structuring and code management of different Salesforce projects, mainly triggers, visualforces, workflows ,REST service integrations and test classes.
- Diving, integration and publishment in Heroku of a Java SMSes data sending app integrated with NodeJs, Marketing cloud, SFDC and Talend platforms by REST services.
- Main responsible of the development and publishment in Heroku of a NodeJs Web service
 app which purpose was the massive user data sending to a SMSes sending data Company as
 well as the storage of the responses received in PostgresSQL.
- Maintenance and creation of new Angular modules for a car's concessionaire app.

March 2016 – February 2017

SOFTWARE JUNIOR DEVELOPER - (DxD Applications & IT Solutions)

 Assistance to software courses related to the competences: SAP (ABAP modality), Java and Salesforce.

- Participation in several maintenance Salesforce projects where I grew up as code developer and platform admin.
 Full stack developer in an energy market project to simulate some Salesforce functionalities
 - Full stack developer in an energy market project to simulate some Salesforce functionalities
 through a Java Web application. Thanks to this project, I learnt and explored several set of
 tools such as: Spring MVC, Spring Hibernate, HTML,CSS,jQuery, JSP, Javascript, SQL,
 REST, AJAX..., the study of the Heroku platform and its synchronization with Salesforce
 and the use of Talend tool for massive data migration (ETL).
- More information in: https://sergio-asensio-cv.herokuapp.com

COURSES

March – 2016

April – 2016

SAP Formation Course, AVAP modality

Java Formation Course

Salesforce Formation Course

Angular 6 Formation Course

PRESENTATIONS

October – 2016

October – 2017

Salesforce Course Intructor

Java Course Intructor

CERTIFICATIONS

Java Standard Edition 6 Programmer Certified Professional (Score: 93%)

PUBLICATIONS

Ecuaciones Diferenciales Implícitas y Clasificación de sus Singularidades. (URL: https://zaguan.unizar.es/record/36919/files/TAZ-TFG-2015-4450.pdf)